A Guide to the Morton-Halsey Papers
University of Virginia Library
- I: CORRESPONDENCE
  - IB. CORRESPONDENCE: J. J. HALSEY
    - Topical Correspondence and Papers
      - re Dr. B. B. Halsey's case with the State Board of Medical Examiners, 1885-1886 (Box Box 11)
    - Related Materials:
      - List of Election Times, Electors and Vote in the 1840 Presidential Election, ca. 1840 (Box Box 11)
      - Registration Form of Andrew Johnson, "a person of colour", 1855 (Box Box 11)
      - Essays and Verse by J. J. Halsey, 1861, n.d. (Box Box 11)
      - 2 pages from notebook of M[ildred] J. Halsey re home life and Union occupation of area, with note to "Dear Husband" [ J. J. Halsey], 1863 May 5-17 (Box Box 11)
      - Student Report Cards, Mathematic Problems, School Assignments, 1863-1897, n.d. (Box Box 11)
      - Architecture Plans and Building Estimates re " Lessland", 1870 (Box Box 11)
      - Examinations of B. B. Halsey at Williston Seminary, 1881, n.d. (Box Box 12)
      - Pocket Address Book of J. J. Halsey, including recipes, home remedies and personal accounts, 1884-1892 (Box Box 12)
      - Miscellaneous papers from Pocket Address Book of J. J. Halsey, 1884-1892 (Box Box 12)
      - Accounts of J. J. Halsey re tuition, board and incidental expenses of his grand-daughter, Irena Louisa Halsey at Piedmont Female Institute, 1893-1894 (Box Box 12)
      - Recipes and Home Remedies (Box Box 12)
      - Miscellaneous Papers, 1882-1857 (Box Box 12)
  - IC. CORRESPONDENCE: WINSTON FAMILY
    - Winston Family Correspondence, 1846-1872, n.d.; (8 folders) (Box Box 12)
- II: FINANCIAL AND LEGAL PAPERS
  - IIA. FINANCIAL AND LEGAL PAPERS: PACKETS
    - Individuals:
      - Austin, William C., ca. 1853-1857 (Box Box 12)
      - Beechwood and Mallory (Box Box 12)
      - Blackwell, John and Hannah, ca. 1857-1882 (Box Box 12)
      - Britt, Charles G., and Beckham, James, ca. 1852-1853 (Box Box 12)
      - Brown, Bushrod W., ca. 1858-1891 (Box Box 12)
      - Brown, Thomas, ca. 1810-1869 (Box Box 12)
      - Bunley, Frances and Susie, ca. 1818-1825 (Box Box 12)
      - Carter, M. A., 1851 (Box Box 12)
      - Clark, John, James, and Reuben, 1869 (Box Box 12)
      - Clark, William D., ca. 1863-1873 (Box Box 12)
      - Costello, Timothy, 1869-1870 (Box Box 12)
      - Crittenden, J. W., 1850-1859 (Box Box 12)
      - Daniel, Sarah A., 1862-1865 (Box Box 12)
      - Eliason, William P., 1858-1859 (Box Box 12)
      - Everheart, Adam, 1871 (Box Box 12)
      - Gaurd, John, 1850-1859 (Box Box 12)
      - Glaspell, John and Mary, 1850-1859 (Box Box 12)
      - Gray Family, 1880-1889 (Box Box 12)
      - Green, Thomas I., ca. 1855-1857 (Box Box 13)
      - Hall, R. W., 1838-1882 (Box Box 13)
      - Hansbrough, James, 1805-1870 (Box Box 13)
      - Hansbrough, Jane and Peter, 1837-1862 (Box Box 13)
      - Hunton, Eppa, 1877-1882 (Box Box 13)
      - Hutchenson, Parchal, ca. 1874-1891 (Box Box 13)
      - Johnson, Philip, 1868-1874 (Box Box 13)
      - Jones, James, 1867-1869 (Box Box 13)
      - Keith, Thomas A., 1860-1866 (Box Box 13)
      - Morton, George, 1857-1890 (Box Box 13)
      - Morton, Thomas, 1850 (Box Box 13)
      - Nalle, Martin and Philip, 1830-1859 (Box Box 13)
      - Nelson, Lewis, 1867 (Box Box 13)
      - Pannill, George, 1875 (Box Box 13)
      - Payne, Charles B., 1874 (Box Box 13)
      - Peyton, W. S., ca. 1847-1869 (Box Box 13)
      - Porter, Colonel John A., ca. 1857-1866 (Box Box 13)
      - Rayland, John C., 1859-1866 (Box Box 13)
      - Rixey, William, 1850-1869 (Box Box 13)
      - Robins, Reverend W. F., 1869-1885 (Box Box 13)
      - Shadrack, J. W., and Somerville, John H., 1874 (Box Box 13)
      - Shadrack, Samuel, ca. 1832-1878 (Box Box 13)
      - Sleet, George A., ca. 1850-1859 (Box Box 13)
      - Smith, Daniel W., 1843-1844 (Box Box 14)
      - Somerville, James, 1840-1860 (Box Box 14)
      - Stearns, E. W., ca. 1840-1890 (Box Box 14)
      - Steeles Tavern, Augusta County, Virginia, 1857-1860 (Box Box 14)
      - Stringfellow, James L., 1860-1882 (Box Box 14)
      - Terrill, John, 1871 (Box Box 14)
      - Van Wyck, C. R. and Winston, L. D., 1886, n.d. (Box Box 14)
      - Vaughan, John, 1860, 1870, 1875 (Box Box 14)
      - Waugh, C. S. and Waugh, N. B., 1869, 1877 (Box Box 14)
      - Wharton, [John] Thomas Morton and Children, 1858-1859 (Box Box 14)
      - Wharton and Nalle, ca. 1866 (Box Box 14)
      - Wharton, William, 1850-1859 (Box Box 14)
      - Wharton, William and Halsey, J. J., ca. 1842-1874 (Box Box 14)
      - Wharton, William and Halsey, J. J. re Saw Mill, ca. 1866 (Box Box 14)
      - Williams, Colonel Bruce, ca. 1830-1866 (Box Box 14)
      - Winston, Walter C., 1945-1947 (Box Box 15)
      - Winston Family, 1830-1860 (Box Box 15)
      - Willis, Isaac, ca. 1865-1881 (Box Box 15)
    - Jeremiah Morton
      - Financial and Legal Papers of Jeremiah Morton, 1823-1859; (5 folders) (Box Box 15)
      - Financial and Legal Papers of Jeremiah Morton, 1850-1869; (6 folders) (Box Box 16)
      - Financial and Legal Papers of Jeremiah Morton, 1870-1879, n.d.; (2 folders) (Box Box 17)
    - J. J. Halsey
      - Financial and Legal Papers of J. J. Halsey, 1843-1862; (11 folders) (Box Box 17)
      - Financial and Legal Papers of J. J. Halsey, 1867-1889, n.d.; (4 folders) (Box Box 18)
  - IIB. FINANCIAL AND LEGAL PAPERS: FINANCIAL PAPERS
    - Accounts and Itemized Receipts
      - Accounts and Itemized Receipts, 1800-1859; (6 folders) (Box Box 18)
      - Accounts and Itemized Receipts, 1850-1859; (6 folders) (Box Box 19)
      - Accounts and Itemized Receipts, 1850-1869; (6 folders) (Box Box 20)
      - Accounts and Itemized Receipts, 1860-1894, n.d.; (6 folders) (Box Box 21)
    - Bills and Receipts
      - Bills and Receipts, 1800-1859; (7 folders) (Box Box 22)
      - Bills and Receipts, 1850-1859; (7 folders) (Box Box 23)
      - Bills and Receipts, 1850-1859; (7 folders) (Box Box 24)
      - Bills and Receipts, 1850-1859; (7 folders) (Box Box 25)
      - Bills and Receipts, 1860-1869; (7 folders) (Box Box 26)
      - Bills and Receipts, 1860-1879; (7 folders) (Box Box 27)
      - Bills and Receipts, 1870-1889; (6 folders) (Box Box 28)
      - Bills and Receipts, 1880-1895, n.d.; (4 folders) (Box Box 29)
    - Tax Receipts
      - A thru Z, ca. 1810-1899; (2 folders) (Box Box 29)
      - Jeremiah Morton, 1845-1872 (Box Box 29)
      - J. J. Halsey, 1847-1878 (Box Box 29)
      - J. Morton Halsey, 1885-1889 (Box Box 29)
    - Checks
      - Checks, ca. 1800-1895; (2 folders) (Box Box 29)
      - Checks, ca. 1800-1895; (2 folders) (Box Box 30)
    - Charts, Tables, and Lists of Numbers
      - Charts, Tables, and Lists of Numbers (Box Box 30)
  - IIC. FINANCIAL AND LEGAL PAPERS: LEGAL PAPERS
    - General Legal Papers
      - Legal Papers, 1800-1866; (6 folders) (Box Box 30)
      - Legal Papers, 1867-1897, n.d. (Box Box 31)
    - Promissory Notes
      - Promissory Notes, 1800-1895; (4 folders) (Box Box 31)
    - Wills
      - Wills, 1848-1887 (Box Box 31)
    - Bankruptcy
      - Bankruptcy, 1868-1876 (Box Box 32)
    - Insurance
      - Insurance, 1849-1876 (Box Box 32)
    - Land Transactions and Surveys
      - Land Transactions and Surveys, 1800-1879; (4 folders) (Box Box 32)
      - Land Transactions and Surveys, 1880-1889, n.d.; (2 folders) (Box Box 33)
    - Court Related Materials
      - Notes re Laws and Court Cases, 1837-1867, n.d. (Box Box 33)
      - Bills of Complaint, 1843-1886 (Box Box 33)
      - Summons, 1844-1887 (Box Box 33)
      - Opinions, Answers to Bills of Complaint, 1853-1880 (Box Box 33)
      - Statements of Case, 1857-1864, n.d. (Box Box 33)
      - Court Notices, 1857-1878 (Box Box 33)
- III. PRINTED MATERIAL
  - Programs, 1843, 1881-1884 (Box Box 34)
  - Forms re Land, Wills, Indentures, Stocks, Bankruptcy, 1850-1874 (Box Box 34)
  - Laws and Printed Legal Material, 1850-1881, n.d. (Box Box 34)
  - Broadsides and Advertisements (See also: Oversize Material Removed from Scrapbooks), 1854-1894, n.d (Box Box 34)
  - Circular Letters, 1856-1877, 1894 (Box Box 34)
  - Business Cards, 1857, 1877, 1900, n.d. (Box Box 34)
  - Pamphlets and Brochures, 1866-1888, n.d. (Box Box 34)
  - Personal Cards and Invitations, 1884, 1902-1911, n.d. (Box Box 34)
  - Tintype Photograph: Students Rooming in Senior Entrance, North Hall, n.d. (Box Box 34)
  - Miscellaneous, 1870, 1911, n.d. (Box Box 34)
- IV. LEDGERS
  - IVA. LEDGERS: VOLUMES OF JEREMIAH MORTON
    - Mathematics Notebook, 1817; 1 (Box Box 35)
    - Personal Account Books/Notebook, 1823-1844; 2 (Box Box 35)
    - Ledger, 1836-1844; 3 (Box Box 35)
  - IVB. LEDGERS: MEDICAL VOLUMES
    - Journal, 1812-1815; 4 (Box Box 35)
    - Journal, 1815-1819; 5 (Box Box 35)
    - Ledger, index labelled "Ledger B," Dr. R. Briggs, 1811-1819; 6 (Box Box 36)
  - IVC. LEDGERS: OTHER VOLUMES
    - Daybook, Parnassas Mills, Racoon Ford, 1856-1868; 7 (Box Oversize)
    - John A. Porter, Nalle, Fishback, & Co., 1850 Jan-Dec; 8 (Box Box 36)
    - Journal, Saw Mill Customers, 1866-1868; 9 (Box Box 36)
    - Ledger, index, 1822-1826; 10 (Box Box 37)
    - Ledger, John A. Porter, 1845-1862; 11 (Box Oversize)
    - Index (Alphabetical) to Ledger 11, John A. Porter, 1856; 11a (Box Box 37)
    - Ledger, index, 1851-1852; 12 (Box Box 37)
    - Ledger, 1853-1859; 13 (Box Box 37)
    - Ledger, B. W. B[rown], 1860-1861; 14 (Box Box 37)
    - Ledger, Charles B. Porter Ledger "H", 1862-1867; 15 (Box Oversize)
    - Ledger, B. W. Brown, 1862-1869; 16 (Box Box 37)
    - Ledger, index, 1866-1869; 17 (Box Box 37)
    - Ledger/Journal, index, 1850-1856, 1871-1872; 18 (Box Oversize)
    - Miscellaneous Material from Volumes 2 and 3, 1817-1844 (Box Box 38)
    - Miscellaneous Material from Volume 8, ca. 1852-1857 (Box Box 38)
    - Miscellaneous Material from Volume 11, ca. 1857-1865 (Box Box 38)
    - Miscellaneous Material from Volume 12: Accounts and Legal Papers, ca. 1857-1882 (Box Box 38)
    - Miscellaneous Material from Volume 12: Maps, Land Transactions, Drawings, and Printed Material, 1877, n.d. (Box Box 38)
    - Miscellaneous Material from Volume 15: Financial and Legal Papers, ca. 1862-1887 (Box Box 38)
    - Miscellaneous Material from Volume 15: Pamphlets, Charts, Broadsides, and Other Printed Material, 1878-1883, n.d. (Box Box 38)
    - Miscellaneous Material from Volume 15: Drawings, Architecture Plans, Maps and Surveys (Box Box 38)
    - Miscellaneous Material from Volume 18: Land Transactions, Advertisements, Broadsides, ca. 1866-1887 (Box Box 38)
    - Page from Ledger of Tree-Hill Garden and Orchard, 1858 Apr 1 (Box Box 38)
- V. ENVELOPES, WRAPPINGS, AND FRAGMENTS
  - Envelopes with Annotations, ca. 1800-1899; (2 folders) (Box Box 38)
  - Wrappings with Annotations, ca. 1800-1899 (Box Box 38)
  - Wrappings with Annotations, ca. 1800-1899 (Box Box 39)
  - Wrappings, Envelopes, and Fragments, ca. 1800-1899; (3 folders) (Box Box 39)
- VI. OVERSIZE
  - Broadsides, 1854-1886 (Box Oversize)
  - Accounts of J. J. Halsey, 1869-1877 (Box Oversize)
  - Surveys and Maps, 1883, n.d. (Box Oversize)